ABEY KURIAN

Phone: 021 0820 3894, Email: abeykurian94@gmail.com LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/abeykurian/

PROFILE

I recently graduated with a Diploma in Information Technology (Level 7). My bachelor's degree was in engineering (Information technology). I have more than two years of software testing experience and I am looking to join a company that I can grow my career in New Zealand with and meet awesome people at the same time

KEY AKILLS& ATTRIBUTES

- Strong experience in Manual Testing
- Prior experience with test management tools like JIRA Mantis and Taiga.
- Strong experience in creating and executing test cases
- Performing system, integration, regression, and end to end testing.
- A good understanding of agile methodology
- Ready to learn new skills
- Ability to work independently and part of a team
- Excellent communication skills.

EDUCATION

WELLINGTON INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY (WelTec)

2019-2020

Graduate Diploma in Information Technology - (Level 7)

Subject involved in the course work:

- Project Management
- Software Testing
- Information Security
- System Analysis and Design
- Web Application Development

KARUNYA UNIVERSITY

2011-2016

Graduated in Bachelor of Technology in Information Technology

Personal Interests and Hobbies

- Traveling.
- Elderly care
- Volunteer Work

CAREER SUMMARY

2020 - Present

IT DESKTOP SUPPORT

Axiom Technologies

VOLUNTEER SOFTWARE TESTER

2020 - Present

Open Law NZ Limited, New Zealand

Health Care Assistant

2020 - Present

Woburn Home, Wellington

COMMERCIAL CLEANER Spotless, Wellington	2020 - 2021
KITCHEN HAND & KITCHEN PORTER Spice traders & Mexico restaurant, Wellington	2019 – 2020
QUALITY ANALYST MWT Technologies, India	2016 – 2019

EXPERTISE

Manual Testing Testcase Design

Test Strategy & Planning JIRA

Knowledge of software test life cycle Manual Testing

Regression Testing Selenium web driver

Regression Testing ASP.NET MVC Framework

SELECTED ROLES, RESPONSIBILITIES & ACHIEVEMENTS

IT DESKTOP SUPPORT	2020-Present
--------------------	--------------

Axiom Technologies

SOFTWARE TESTER – VOLUNTEER 2020 – Present

Open Law NZ

Open Law NZ is a new, free legal research platform for New Zealanders.

- My role is to get involved in Cross-browser testing and report and communicate through slack.
- Different tools including Lambda test are used to learn the working of website on different platforms.
- Microsoft team are used for team meetings.
- **Tools and Methodologies**: manual testing, Slack, Lambda Test Selenium Web driver, Microsoft Teams.

QUALITY ANALYST 2016-2019

MWT TECHNOLOGIES

MWT Technologies reigns as a force to reckon with in the software development sphere and recognized as a next-generation information solution consulting firm with the technical know-how and expertise to help businesses achieve a dynamic online market presence.

My responsibilities include:

- Review user requirements documents to ensure that requirements are testable.
- Design and develop tests for software and systems to detect faults
- Keep written records of defects and bugs that are discovered during testing
- develop test plans and test cases by reviewing the product requirements and specifications
- Responding promptly to service issues, requests and undertaken technical troubleshooting and root cause analysis
- Managed base level IT support to clients and support them with software Issues and troubleshooting
- Log all actions undertaken in the Jira ticket following the known company practice
- Design and develop test automation tools and scripts
- Involve in risk analysis to determine areas of high probable risk and define severity and priority of each task
- Help documentation team to review technical documentation including user manuals, technical specifications
- Respond to customer requests raised through Jira Service Desk, phone, or email

Tools and Methodologies: Manual testing, JIRA, Mantis, Selenium IDE, Selenium Web driver, AGILE, Visual Studio, Excel, JMeter.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Automation Testing: Knowledge in Selenium Web

driver and JMeter

Programming Language: Basic java, Knowledge in

ASP.NET MVC Framework

Security Testing: Knowledge in Nmap and Wireshark

Tracking tools: JIRA, Mantis

AWARDS & RECOGNITIONS

• Certificate of success -July 220 winner from Spotless

REFERENCES

References available upon request